hello thanks for listening to The Grow
Your Life podcast my name is Jeremiah
Kowski and on this podcast I show
coaches mentors and trainers how to grow
their businesses and get more clients
online now in this episode I want to
talk to you about the best methods
models and approaches for getting
clients people ask me this all the time
what are the best approaches that you
can use and simply put it's about having
a conversation or a connection with
someone but those do not have to happen
one to one so there's different ways of
having conversations and connections
with people you can totally go by
phone uh you could do a direct message
but there's other ways people don't
always think about such as
comments on social media right such as
and and here's another one
pre-recorded content okay and any time
that we are marketing our business as
coaches and mentors we're trying to
facilitate the internal dialogue and
conversation so people have two
different types of conversations they
have the
inner conversation that they're having
with themselves they're they're talking
internally with themselves and they're
deciding whether they want to work with
you they're also having
Inner Circle conversations which is the
people around them that are in their
life the people that they trust and the
people that they want to engage with and
then they also have them with you okay
so this is with themselves this is with
those that are closest to them and then
these are with you or your team so these
are three stages of conversations that
people can have if you make a post on
social media and somebody comments and
then you comment back even just them
commenting is a form of a conversation
if they watch pre-recorded content the
internal dialogue that they have by
listening to it by us listening to this
right now any thoughts or ideas that you
have listening to this podcast are an
internal conversation that you're having
with yourself so even though I'm
monologuing because you're another
person who's on the receiving end of
this listening there is a conversation
that starts to happen between us even
though we've not necessarily conversed
directly it begins and so this is really
what we're
facilitating in any form of marketing to
get clients is this type of a
conversation and so again this could be
in the form of a webinar this could be
in the form of a challenge this could be
in the form of any different kind of
marketing that we end up doing realizing
that it doesn't have to look one way or
the other and actually like we need to
stop looking at them like they're all
different
okay what they are is they're a part of
the journey that our Prospect goes
on before somebody purchases from us our
coaching okay let's work back backwards
from here here's Sally right here we're
going to draw Sally okay my little stick
figure and this is Sally when she
purchases a uh let's say a $2,000
coaching program with you okay here's
Sally the day she was born all right and
so somewhere along the line from the
time that she was born to here she was a
good Prospect for you to talk to maybe
you know she was 5 years old right here
got to get them young right no that's a
terrible time right you're not going to
start marketing to your prospect at that
point now television does media does
that's a whole other conversation about
how it indoctrinates children and things
like that into literally marketing
funnels big Pharma literally markets to
Children through sugary
cereal to get them hooked on the
pharmaceutical industry pretty
interesting right but we're not we're
not in that game we're in a we're in a
much more ethical game where we're
helping people who have problems and so
throughout this stage of life we got age
25 35 right about here she starts
deciding
hm I've made some decisions during this
time that I'm not a big fan of and I
need to solve a problem and so from the
time she's about 35 until the age of 45
right here this is 10
years she's on a discovery Journey so
let's zoom in right here cuz we don't
really need to look at the whole
lifespan of her right there but let's
just look at the last 10 years
okay
Sally in the last 10 years right she's
35 years old right here
okay and then she purchases your
coaching right here at the age of 45
let's say just for the sake of the
example her decision is that she wants
to learn how to transition out of a
career that she hates okay but it take
but it took her 10
years of
struggle life
events
changes
moments before she was ready to make a
purchase over here to actually solve
this problem because she was in a dead
end job that she hated and every time
she felt like she was making progress it
was two steps forward one step back two
steps forward one step back two steps
forward one step back okay it's
literally the life cycle of most people
that they deal with and so you show up
with a solution to say Hey what if
instead of two steps for one step back
we could take five steps forward and
then three more and then maybe one step
back because you know that's the circle
of life in reality it happens we all end
up you know things happen they come up
situations happen but instead of it
being two steps forward one step back
one of it's seven or eight and then you
actually are making more forward
momentum and more progress and she's
like okay I'll buy that I've been doing
this model for 10 years and I'm 35 and I
want to make a change so she's going to
make an investment with you of $2,000 so
there is a moment in time where you end
up meeting Sally and that's right here
okay you end up meeting her and maybe
she's 44 years old right here see you
could try to Market to Sally everywhere
up to this moment in time but she might
not have been ready for the thing that
you
offer okay and so the first thing that
we want to do to when we get clients is
we want we want to make sure that
they're qualified for the thing that
we're actually offering them we want to
make sure that they're actually in a
position to be ready for it that they
actually desire it now the second part
is that when we sell to people we have
to learn to be really really good at the
ability to persuade people to take
action and to get off the fence because
we help them identify that they keep
doing the same thing over and over and
over again and expecting a different
result that nothing is going to change
for them and when people have a desire
to do something and to make a change
they're going to do it when they see a
solution that's better than everything
else that they've
tried and we can at least mitigate the
risk or the fear provide safety provide
security a lot of people dealt with
trauma they've dealt with issues they're
skeptical so we have to address all of
that in our marketing and so what you do
is you identify right here a form of
messaging that communicates and not
merely communicates but connects deeply
at the core of why Sally wants to make a
change okay and so when we do this we're
able to show up in her life through a
number of different Avenues let's say
social media the algorithms will start
showing up because number one her
reticular activating system is firing
and ends up noticing the stuff that she
that we're talking about the reticular
activating system is this thing in your
brain that when you're seeking out
something you end up noticing more of it
so when she's starting to look for these
things she starts to notice more of what
she's looking for and then the social
media algorithms are designed if she's
engaging with content based on that to
give and feed more content similar to
and like that okay so based on that what
we want to identify is what
amplifies the right message at the right
time to the right person through our
social media and what this does is this
facilitates just it's a fancy word for
helps create start uh get the mechanisms
going it's part of the machine to get
things moving forward to help her make
decision 2024 not the one for the
president but the decision to work with
you as a
client and then what you get to do is
you get get to facilitate that
conversation internally with people that
she knows or with you and then what ends
up happening is is that when you can hit
all those markers provide
safety show and providing safety really
is one of the most number one things you
can do it really is and show and
demonstrate
value you you you you own the result
that she's going to receive you say okay
this is what you're going to get and I'm
going to help you get there and you
start owning that
fact and so when you can gather the
right person at the right time in front
of you with the right
messaging to facilitate any form of a
conversation could be a social media
comment could be on a webinar could be
on a YouTube video could be on a podcast
episode the right person with the right
message at the right time who's looking
for the right
information will then say huh that's
what I want and they will seek out to
solve that problem so what you end up
doing is you end up scratching the itch
they already have and pointing it out
and what ends up happening is they start
to notice oh wow I have I have an issue
going on here I have this rash that's
not going away right I have this redness
that's not working for me and I need to
solve this in my life and then you show
up not not passively and this is where
we got to got to get it right and this
is where most people miss it as they
take a passive Approach at this point
well if she wants it she'll find me
she'll come find me and I'll I'm just
going to give her agency and autonomy to
be able to find me on her
own through my socials and hopefully
maybe she'll like me enough to ask for
help that's a romantic fairy tale idea
that feels great but in reality it never
works out that way it doesn't I've been
doing this for 21 years and it never
works out in the fairy tale idea that
well how we think it would as far as
that goes and so understanding that
we're not in a fairy tale means we got
to go out there and be intentional to
close the sale
to start connecting the dots and saying
hey are you ready to make a change and
we start promising these outcomes and
these results and we start owning those
outcomes for
people and we charge money for it now if
you're hesitant to charge money you
might need to address those monetary
beliefs we live in a culture today that
starts demonizing capitalism and that's
terrible that it does that because it's
an incredible vehicle for making the
world a better place and so understand
that as coaches and and as mentors we
have a desire for impact but we got to
bring in some income we got to bring in
some cash flow and we got to actually
start bringing in clients okay so the
way that you do this is you figure out
what is the right message at the right
time to the right person that gets them
to take action now here's the cool thing
about this you don't have to
guess okay there is so many mechanisms
that we can use to be able to facilitate
this you can use artificial intelligence
to help you you can go on Amazon look at
books that are written you can look at
what your competitors are using to
Market you can look at what others are
talking about on podcast and YouTube and
social media and then this gives you
ideas based on the the the responses and
the outcome and the ideas that people
are sharing if you're so focused on
being the number one most original idea
that nobody's ever thought of before and
that's what you're trying to do I you
know we not encouraging you to
plagiarize anybody at all you look at
what is happening in your niche in your
market and then what can we learn from
to model into your messaging that fits
what Sally wants you don't need to
reinvent the wheel it's stupidity to
reinvent the wheel it really is
okay you don't need to because there are
literally thousands of other coaches
course creaders and mentors that have
solved a lot of the wheel for you and
figured out how to connect with people
and so then what you can do is you can
learn what are those trigger words what
are those key words what are those
things that get the algorithm to show my
content more to people how do I show up
in front of the right people and that's
exactly what I Mentor people on in our
client growth accelerator program I'd
love for you to join us in there so what
we work with people on every single week
is dialing in that messaging to get more
clients to attract the right people to
them okay we'd love to have you join
that with us we'd love to have you join
any of our trainings that we have
subscribe to our Channel and and stay
connected because if you're a coach if
you're a course creator if you're a
mentor teacher trainer and you want to
know how do I get more clients we got
the answers for you and we can help you
do that okay and so if you have been
trying to figure this out you got to
learn it's not that you don't know how
to talk it's not that you don't know how
to communicate but you got to learn what
is the right Cadence tone and language
to communicate with
people to close the sale and to get
people to make a buying decision and and
so to be able to do that is that people
move towards pleasure and away from pain
we understand this right okay so we end
up showing people what they desire what
is the most pleasurable fantasy desire
that they have that we can then move
them towards and then we point out by
the way if you're not experiencing this
you're probably experiencing all of this
struggle that you want to move away from
and people say we can say listen we can
eliminate all that we can get you over
here to this this Fantastical idea that
you
have and then that attracts people to us
and then that's what closes sales now
you might be saying well what if I can't
deliver on those results well the truth
is yes you want to make sure that you're
marketing with what you can deliver on
results with it's actually not even
legal to to not do that okay but 100% of
the people that you work with are not
going to get those results here's an
example okay I work with clients I have
clients that I've helped build their
businesses to over $20
million I've built businesses over $10
million are you going to make $20
million watching this podcast no are you
going to make $100,000 just listening to
this podcast no is everybody who applies
what I teach going to make 1020 million
no absolutely not but if they do apply
it it will start to move things forward
for them much more effectively than I
would say 99% of the other people that
you listen to that are out there I've
been doing this for 21 years and we've
been very successful with it and so
understand that you're not going to
please everybody you're not going to
solve everybody's problems and that's
okay but you want to go out there and
boldly and confidently present your
opportunity and present what you have to
offer with people and confidently talk
as if the right people are in front of
you right now there's a really cool
concept I was listening to a to a book
recently recently it was called The Game
of Life and how to play it uh by Francis
goal shin and it's an it's in book it's
from the 1920s uh but there's a section
in it that really stuck in my mind about
the fact of sort of like preparing for
the thing before it happens and it's
like okay well fake it till you make it
that doesn't sound right that's not what
we're talking about but we're talking
about communicating in a way that
effectively is going to it it assumes
that you're already talking to qualified
people okay it assumes that you're
already talking to the right people as
far as that goes so here's what ends up
happening when you in your marketing and
in your sales communicate in a way that
assumes you're talking to the right
people is that the wrong people will
make themselves known very quickly so
that's really cool is that if you start
talking and communicating as if you're
talking to Sally right here where she's
about ready to make a decision and you
start adjusting your language to to fit
into that
framework um that's great because the
ones that don't fit into that they'll
drop off and there's no harm done there
you
know the ones who it does resonate with
though because you're talking so
specifically to them they're going to be
like oh my gosh how did you know that I
needed this how did you know exactly
what I was going through and they're
going to be like whoa it's like you know
well it's because you you've literally
tailored it and designed it for a very
specific type of person specific stage
of their life Journey specific problem
and that's what dials in your messaging
now there's deeper mechanisms and things
like that that we teach inside of my
coaching program but this is the the
foundation of dialing in all of that is
is making sure that you figure out who
are we talking to what problem they got
what do they desire what outcome do they
want what what what result can we own
that we're going to give them what
transformation are we going to give and
then our process facilitates building
trust with them trust in you trust in
your Product Trust in your program and
Trust in the transformation and result
that you can deliver and when you can
build that trust with people
and it's the right person at the right
time that
like they won't say they won't say no
because it's exactly what they're
looking for it's exactly what they've
been praying for they believe you can
deliver it to it and your messaging was
was aligned to the right person at the
right time and then what's really cool
is the algorithms on social media and
even when we run paid advertising we
start to show the offer to the right
people people at the right time and that
makes it really really exciting and that
also brings the cost way way down in our
marketing all right so listen if you are
a coach Mentor trainer and you want to
know how to do all this I'd love to help
you I'd love to work with you make sure
that you subscribe to this
podcast make sure that you plug into the
different content that we have and jump
into my accelerator program we'd love to
have you in there all right we'll talk
soon have a good one
[Music]
[Applause]
oh